Lisa Michelle Hill

lisahill207@gmail.com (703) 309-7033 www.lisahill.dev linkedin.com/in/lisa-m-hill

Objective		
	After 9 years as a higher education professional, I am following my passion for technology. Combining my professional experiences in program management and customer success with strom my recent B.S. in Web & Digital Design, I am seeking employment as a Front-End Developer.	kills
Education		
	B.S., Web & Digital Design	2023
	University of Maryland Global Campus	
	M.Ed., Student Personnel in Higher Education. University of Florida	2016
	B.A., Humanities, Science and Environment Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University	2014
Technical Skills		
	Languages	
	• HTML5	
	• CSS3	

Professional Experience

JavaScript (ES14)

Towson University - Academic Advising, Retention, and Completion Office Academic Advisor for Transferring and First-Year Students

2019 – Present

- Hire, train, and supervise 8 student academic advisor undergraduate student employees.
- Promote academic success by advising 40 first-year freshmen in one-to-one, small group, large group, and online settings.
- Increase retention by providing interventions and support for students on academic alert, academic warning, and academic probation.
- Strengthen campus partnerships by liaising and networking with faculty and staff advisors in the College of Liberal Arts.
- Improve the transfer experience by providing appropriate and effective academic advising to students from the pre-admissions process, through post-matriculation.

Towson University - Office of Civic Engagement & Social Responsibility Coordinator of Community Service

2017 - 2019

- Hire, train, and supervise one graduate assistant and 7 undergraduate employees.
- Advise Alternative Break Connections (ABC) student organization leadership board, including managing \$40,000 operating budget and providing on-call assistance for all domestic and international student travel.
- Promote mutually beneficial programming and maintain partnerships with over 60 regional nonprofits.

Lisa Michelle Hill

lisahill207@gmail.com (703) 309-7033 www.lisahill.dev linkedin.com/in/lisa-m-hill

- Plan and implement weeklong volunteer, experiential, and educational programming as part of Hunger & Homelessness Awareness Week, and National Volunteer Week.
- Manage transportation funding and logistics for BTU, a presidential initiative to promote partnerships between Towson University and the greater Baltimore region.

Virginia Tech - VT Engage: The Community Learning Collaborative Interim Service Learning Coordinator

2016-2017

- Develop curriculum and facilitate weekly trainings for STEP UP student leaders on topics including reflection, facilitation, group development process, and social issue education.
- Create materials and procedures for integrating learning outcomes and enhanced educational programming into student led immersion programs.
- Partner with campus departments and faculty members to create meaningful community engagement experiences.

Volunteer Experience

Co-Leader, Girl Scout of Central Maryland Council

2017 - 2020

- Plan and facilitate badge activities for troop of 10 girls.
- Mentor scouts both as part of Girl Scouts and outside of troop activities.